CLERK 1: Next, pIease.
下一位
Come on, come on.
快点…
Name.
名字
Gus Gorman.
格斯高曼
Ah, yes. August Gorman.
有了，格斯高曼
Have you Iooked for work this week?
你希望这星期说上班吗？
-Yes. -What kind?
- 是的！ - 想做什么？
-Kitchen technician. -Dishwasher. Any Iuck?
- 厨房技师 - 洗盘子，找到了吗？
No, but--
不，但是…
Mr. Gorman, according to our records, you've been unempIoyed for 36 weeks.
高曼先生，根据资料显示 你已经36个星期没工作了
No, it's 35.
不对，只有35个星期
Not counting this week.
这星期不算
You secured empIoyment in June as a messenger and were discharged after...
你上一份工作 是在保全公司送信
-...one day for Iosing-- -No, they said I ost it.
- 只做一天就… - 不是，他们说我把信搞丢了
I did not ose it! It was stoIen by a pickpocket.
但我根本没有弄丢 是被别人偷走的
A teIevis on set?
一部电视机？
It was a teeny-tiny, teeny-weensy Japanese te evision set.
是一部日本超小型 迷你电视机
The other empIoyment you found was in a fast-food joint, which Iasted...
然后你又在一家速食店工作 只做了…
...28 minutes?
28分钟
That's some kind of record. TaIk about fast.
你的记录居然都是这样 真是快
Those peop e are crazy. They expect you to Iearn that stuff in one day.
你知道那些人都是疯子 要你在一天内学会所有的事情
''Ho d the Iettuce. HoId the ketchup. Can I have some sauce, p ease?"
要拿生菜、拿蕃茄酱 然后又要酱汁
-Mr. Gorman-- -"Two buns. No buns. Some cheese."
- 高曼先生… - 要面包，不要面包，又要起司
Mr. Gorman, the c ty of MetropoIis is generous to a fauIt, but--
高曼先生，大都会市对无业游民 是非常仁慈，但是…
I'm not the fauIt!
- 我不是无业游民 - 在失业了36个星期之后
Thirty-s x weeks of Iiv ng off the taxes of hard-work ng citizens.
没有尽到缴税的义务 36个星期了
-Do you know what you are? -Don't caII me a bum, I'm not a bum!
- 你知道你自己目前的处境吗？ - 别说我是无业游民，我不是
You are, I was about to say, no Ionger e igibIe.
你是，而我要说的是 你无法再申请了
-WeII, Iook-- -Next.
- 听着… - 下一位
Wait. What about this week? I need this week!
那这个星期该怎么办？ 我这星期还要过活
Next.
下一位
You mean, that's it?
你是认真的吗？
"F nished," Iike "over"?
确定不能了？
CLERK 2: Next.
下一位
GUS: "Next" as in " bye."
下一位就表示再见
CLERK 2: Next!
下一位！
Name.
名字
Excuse me, brother, can I have a Iight?
对不起，兄弟 可以借个火吗？
-How you doing, AIex? VENDOR: Hi, Jimmy.
- 你好，艾里 - 嗨，吉米
Excuse me.
对不起
MOTHER: Say thank you.
要说谢谢
Way to go, Superman!
太棒了，超人！
VOICE [ON MACHINE]: Your drlnk is on its way.
你的饮料马上说来了
WOMAN: Sir.
老师
Excuse me...
对不起
...but what if you wanna program two biIateraI coordinates at the same time?
但是，有关于这个程式 二个位元同时混合一起运作
You can't do that. It's impossib e.
你不可以这样作，这不可能的
WOMAN: But f you can't -- -Oh, no.
- 但如果你不能的话… - 不！
Computer techno ogy s very advanced, young Iady, but it can't do that.
电脑技术对年轻小姐是很先进 但你不可这样做
WOMAN: But f you think we can't do it that way, what happens--?
如果你觉得我们不能这样作 那么你觉得是不是可以…
GUS: Sir.
老师
TEACHER: Good Lord.
天呀！
How did you do that?
你怎么办到的？
I don't know. I just did it.
我不知道，我说是办到了
PERRY: Who's this? JIMMY: That's him, Ross Webster.
- 他是谁？ - 此是他，罗斯维斯伯
JIMMY: Just after he received the award for Humanitarian of the Year.
他刚得到年度人道奖
He is good-Iooking.
他很英俊
Because I gave him f.2 at a 50th.
因为我用特殊镜头拍的
One th ng I don't understand...
有一件事我不明白
...the point of the story Lois wrote is how Ross got this great honor...
专题的重点采访的是 罗斯维斯伯如何获得这个荣誉
...and you br ng me one picture of him and 15 pictures of this other person.
而你只拍一张他的照片 却拍了十五张她的照片
PERRY: Who is she? -LoreIe Ambrosia. She's Webster's --
- 她是谁？ - 萝苗蕾，她是维斯伯的…
She's just Webster's . Let's eave it at that.
她就是跟着维斯伯 我们不要谈个
PERRY: Who's this other woman? JIMMY: His sister, Vera Webster.
- 这个女人是谁？ - 他的妹妹，佛庄
PERRY: P cture Iooks fuzzy. -What?
- 照片不清楚 - 什么？
The picture's fine, chief. She Iooks I ke that in reaI Iife.
长官，这看起来很清楚 就好像活生生地站在面前
-She's VP of Webscoe Industries. -I reaIIy don't understand you.
- 她是维斯寇集团的副总裁 - 我真的无法明白
A boring banquet and you bring me 3000 boring pictures.
你去参加个无聊宴会 带回来三千张无聊的照片
Yet Superman saves a man from drowning on Third Avenue...
超人今早在第三街 解救快溺死在车里的人
...whiIe you just stand there and you don't bring me one picture!
而你却傻呼呼地站在旁边 竟连一张照片也没拍
Chief, I didn't have my camera with me.
老板，我当时没有带照相机
A photographer eats with his camera. A photographer sIeeps with his camera.
摄影记者吃饭也带着照相机 摄影记者睡觉也带着照相机
-I'm gIad I'm a writer. -Mr. White, pIease.
- 我很庆幸我只是个文字记者 - 怀特先生，请吧
It's t me for you to draw this month's winn ng JINGO number.
需要你抽出本月的幸运号码
Prze is an aII-expenses trip to South America.
奖品是免费到南美的旅游机会
-I don't know why the idiot in CircuIation-- CLARK: Good morning.
- 真是蠢啊 - 早安各位
-Hi, CIark. -Hi, Lois. Morning, Jimmy.
- 嗨，克拉克 - 嗨，露薏丝，早安吉米
You've got mustard on your apeI.
你领口有一点芥末
Excuse me, Mr. White, I hate to interrupt--
怀特先生，我不想打扰你
Sorry. I'm busy. I got a paper to get out here.
对不起，我现在很忙 我有篇文章要赶
It' never rep ace the printing press.
一旦交到印刷厂 就不能再更换的
-What's the number, Mr. White? -Fifty-three.
- 怀特先生，号码是几号？ - 五十三号
-Mr. White-- SECRETARY: Fifty-three!
- 怀特先生… - 五十三号！
CLARK: Mr. White-- -You've got to puII three more numbers.
- 你还要多转出三个号码
I promised I'd caII them back today. What do you think?
但是我答应要回他们电话 你的意思如何？
-WeII, I don't know, Kent-- -I think it'd make a terrific story.
- 我不知道，肯特，我个人是… - 我想一定可以写出精彩的故事
What's a terrific story?
什么样精彩的故事？
Kent's been invited to his high-schooI reunion.
- 他被邀请回去参加高中同学会 - 没错
-Say. CLARK: Yeah.
- 真的 - 是啊
CouId we have the next number?
可以再来把号码转出来吗？
It's practica y an American inst tution. Isn't it?
这是美国的习俗嘛 对吧，吉米？
I don't know, Mr. Kent. Most of the peopIe I know are st I in h gh schooI.
我不知道，我高中的同学 还在念高中
Thirty-three.
33号
What I thought this story would be about, Mr. White, is--
我想这个故事 可以写有关…
SECRETARY: Thirty-three.
33号
--is how much the typicaI smaII town has changed in the ast 15 years.
在过去15年问 典型的小镇究竟有多大转变
Take me, for exampIe:
拿我作个例子
Can I reaIIy go back to m ddIe America now as a MetropoIis sophisticate?
我在接受过大都会的洗礼后 还可以回到美中地区生活吗？
I'm reaIIy excited about this. In fact, I was Iook ng around...
我想到这里就觉得很兴奋 甚至我昨晚…
...in my cIoset Iast night...
在我的衣柜里…
...and I even found my oId h gh-schooI sweater.
找到我高中时代的运动衣
-SmaIIviIIe. -Mr. White.
- 小镇 - 怀特先生
Can I go ahead and make my traveI pIan?
我可以计划到那里去旅游吗？
Same quest on about mine.
我也有同样的问题要问你
TeII your peopIe the prodigaI son and his photographer are coming home.
告诉你那些同学 大记者要衣锦荣归了
Oh, gee, thanks, Mr. White.
谢谢，怀特先生
It sn't easy for me to Iose one of my best reporters.
我要告诉你，对我来说 最好的记者不在身边实在不好
-That's okay. -You deserve the vacation, Lois.
- 没问题的 - 你应该放假，露薏丝
Thank you.
谢谢
Lois, are you going somep ace?
露薏丝，你要去什么地方玩吗？
CIark, you know some peopIe get to go aII the way to Sma viIIe...
克拉克 有人千方百计要去小镇
...and then there are others of us who have to go to Bermuda.
但也有些人 向往着要去百慕达
GoIIy.
天哪
LOIS: Bye. JIMMY: Bye, Miss Lane.
再见
-Have fun. -Mr. Wh te, the next number, pIease.
- 玩得尽兴 - 怀特先生，你还要抽一个号码
WeII, I guess I better be going too.
我想我也该走了
So I'II be going.
那我要走了
Bye.
再见
CouIdn't we get a computer to do this?
难道不能用电脑来做吗？
-Hey, what is this? -First paycheck.
- 这是什么？ - 你的第一份薪水
This is the first rip-off, man! We're supposed to get 225 a week, rght?
但我一个星期 应该有2 25元吧
This says, ''$143.80.'' How am I supposed to l ve on that?
现在只拿到143点8元 这样如何过活？
State tax, federaI tax, socia security tax--
州税，联邦税 社会安全税…
It's so you're stiII getting some money when you hit 65.
等到65岁 你就可以拿到被扣掉的钱了
So I'm getting money when I--? 65?
要等到65岁才拿得到钱？
I want mine now!
但我现在就需要钱！
I want to enjoy it whiIe I'm young. I wanna get up and get down. Boogie.
我要趁年轻享受 没有钱我怎能享受
ActuaIIy, it's probabIy more Iike $143.80 and one ha f cent.
事实上应该有 143点8元再加上半毛钱
There are aIways fractions Ieft over, but big corporations round it down.
总是会有剩余的钱 但是都是公司拿走了
What do I do with haIf a cent? Buy a thoroughbred mouse?
半毛钱有什么用？ 塞牙缝都不够
Everybody Ioses those fract ons?
每个人剩余的钱都被拿走了？
They don't Iose them. You can't Iose what you never got.
不能说被拿走了 因为你根本没有拿到手上过
Then what happens? The company gets them?
然后呢？ 是公司拿走的吗？
They can't be bothered coIIecting that from your paycheck any more than you.
也不是，他们根本不会像你一样 如此在意此事
Then what happens to them?
那钱会如何处理？
WeII, they're just f oating around out there. The computers know where.
只有电脑知道资金的运作情况 知道钱在哪里
How many sugars?
糖要多少？
One and a haIf.
一个半
It's quitting time, Gus. You coming?
下班了，格斯，你还不走？
Yeah. No, actua Iy, I got some stuff to f nish up, so....
嗯，但我还有些事情 没做完，所以…
Working overtime, huh? What are you doing, buddy? Looking for a raise?
加班工作？想干什么？ 想要加薪吗？
Yeah, Iooking for a ra se.
对，想要加薪
GUS: You bet.
好了
JIMMY: But my UncIe A on my father's side, he won't eat her stuffing.
我姑父站在支持我父亲的一边 他不吃她烹调的东西
He says it shouId be cooked on the outside. She cooks it on the inside.
他说火鸡该从外面烤 她却要从里面烤
My mother toId my Aunt HeIen. She's my father's haIf sister.
我妈说，我姑母海伦是我爸的干妹 我告诉过你，对吗？
-And anyway, the fam Iy-- -Hey, hey.
- 总之… - 嘿…
-Look at that. JIMMY: Wow.
你看，哗！
Okay, your choice: You can turn back or puII over tiII it's over.
你可以选择开回去 或是靠边停，等到结束为止
-How Iong wiII it take? -Can't teII w th these fires.
- 要等多久呢？ - 无法判断
I mean, that fire-- That's spreading Iike wiIdfire.
这种火烧起来 会有蔓延的可能
DRIVER: It's just a buiIding burning.
不过只是一栋建筑物着火罢了
It's not just a buiIding. That's a chemica p ant.
一栋建筑物？ 这是化学工厂呀！
You know what I mean. It's Iike-- It's I ke chemicaIs.
你懂我的意思了吧！ 化学工厂起火
If any of that stuff goes up n smoke, we're in for a hairy time around here.
随时可能会有浓烟 将这附近给遮盖住
-CIark. -Yeah?
- 克拉克 - 是
I want you to keep these peopIe distracted.
你替我分散他们的注意力 这样他们才不知道我要干嘛
What are you doing?
你要干什么？
What am doing? Remember what the ch ef said?
干什么？ 你记得老板的话吗？
A photographer aIways goes after a story.
摄影记者永远要配合上报导
That couId be dangerous, Jimmy.
但这很危险的，吉米
Danger goes with the terrtory, Mr. Kent.
危险，它是随时存在的 肯特
HeIp me!
救命！
-How can I heIp? -Get this man a heImet.
- 我能帮得上忙吗？ - 帮他拿顶头盔
-It's you. Forget the heImet. -How bad is it?
- 喔，是你，你来得正好 - 情况如何？
My God, t's a nightmare. Everything's either expIosive or fIammab e or worse.
天呀！超人，这真像一场恶梦 所有的东西不是爆炸就是冒烟
Get the Iadder truck in here.
快把云梯车开过来
-It won't reach. -My God, they're trapped!
- 构不着 - 天呀！他们被困住了！
What's he gonna do? F y them down one at a t me?
他要干什么？ 一次载一个下来吗？
Let's go! Everybody, down there! Move it!
走吧！大家从这里走！快走！
Come on! Hurry up!
来啊！快点！
There you go.
好了
Right down there. Take it easy.
从这里，慢慢来
AII rght. Everybody down there!
好了，所有人都下去！
Sir, get out. I'lI show you the quickest way.
先生，你要离开这里越快越好
Go on. Look after the others. I can't Ieave.
我要照顾这些仪器 不能离开这里
-Why not? -I gotta stay and Iook after those.
- 为何？ - 我要照顾那些物品
That's concentrated BeItric acid.
这些是浓缩的硫化酸
If that stuff heats up over 180 degrees, we've got a cris s...
如果热度超过180度 就会过热燃烧
...that' make this fire Iook Iike a p cn c.
所引起的危机及火势 就不可收拾
SUPERMAN: What does it do?
那要怎么办？
CHEMIST: As Iong as it rema ns stabIe, it's just ordinary acid.
如果保持温度稳定 就没问题
But if it begins to heat up, it' turn voIatiIe.
但一旦开始受热 它就很容易会爆炸
You'lI get a great cIoud of smoke that wiII eat through anything.
就会有很浓的烟雾 会穿透任何的东西
SteeI, concrete, anything.
钢铁，水泥，任何的东西
Who the heII is that?
你在那里搞什么鬼？
FIREMAN: Hey, you! Get off of there! -I'm just gonna get a coupIe more shots.
- 嘿，离开那里！ - 我只是拍几张火灾的照片
TeI them to bring their hoses back here! QuickIy!
叫他们快点来灭火 快点！
JIMMY: HeIp!
救命！
HeIp! Somebody he p me!
救命！有人能救我吗！
-HeIp! -It's aII right.
- 救命！ - 没事了
-Superman! My Ieg. -I got you. Take it easy.
- 超人！我的腿 - 我抓到你了，轻松点
AII right. We'lI go nice and easy.
我们慢慢来
Okay, 'm sorry. AII right? Here we go.
喔，抱歉 好了吗？走罗
Medics! Over here, pIease.
担架！快过来
That's it. Here you go.
好了，可以了
Go easy. It's the Ieft Ieg.
轻轻地，他左腿骨折了
-My camera. -Yeah.
- 照相机 - 是
It's a cIean break right across the fibuIa.
只是单纯的骨折
-My camera. -Sorry, J mmy. You' I be okay.
- 我的照相机 - 抱歉，吉米，你会没事的
Get that f re out, otherwise there'lI be an ac d cIoud a I over the Eastern seaboard.
你们要集中水扑灭实验室的火 不然里面的硫化酸会过热爆炸
FIREMAN 1: The pump house is gone! FIREMAN 2: What?
- 天啊，抽水车没作用了！ - 什么？
FIREMAN 1: The pump house! -We've Iost the water pressure!
- 抽水车！ - 我们抽不到水了！
-We've got to have water! -How?
- 我们要找到水来！ - 要怎么找？
Lake Comooga's five miIes from here. We'd need a five-miIe hose!
卡摩嘉湖离这里五哩路 五哩的远水救不了近火
-Where's this Iake? -That way.
- 湖在哪里？ - 那边
TeII them it's hopeIess.
- 告诉他们没希望了 - 是你说水源充足的！
Water!
水来了！
I teII you, that man's a miracIe!
真不敢相信，那人是个奇
WOMAN: CaroI, you got gorgeous!
卡罗，你真漂亮！
Look at you.
看看你
BRAD: That was against Mid-City. I'lI never forget t.
那次对抗城中队，我永生难忘
Fourth quarter, score was t ed...
第四节，打成平手
...we're back at the 25-yard Iine.
我们在二十五码线上
Coach sends in a pIay, Right FIanker Option.
教练下达指令，右翼突破
You reaIIy have grown, C ark.
你真的长大了不少，克拉克
You Iook very weII, M ss Bann ster.
你身体也不错，班尼丝太太
I can't compIa n. take the sta rs a ittIe s ow and I have these spe Is.
算是不错了 虽然爬楼梯慢点，记忆还不错
But reaIIy, I can't compIain.
我真的算不错了
Lana?
拉娜？
Clark?
克拉克？
WouId you excuse me? There's someone I'd rea y Iike to say he Io to.
对不起 我有别的朋友来，要去打个招呼
Lana?
拉娜？
-Lana Lang? It's great to see you. -CIark.
- 蓝拉娜？真高兴见到你 - 克拉克
-You Iook wonderfuI. -Me? No, you Iook--
- 你看来师极了 - 不，你才是…
-Let me g ve you a hand with that. -No, no. I can manage.
- 我来帮你 - 不用，我自己可以
This is the first time you've come back since your mom passed away.
这是自从你妈过世后 你第一次从大都会回来
Yeah. I'm sorry.
对的，对不起
CLARK: I heard that you and...
我听说是你和…
-...DonaId sp it up. LANA: Did you eat yet?
- 唐诺分手了？ - 你吃了没？
No.
还没
Beg your pardon. Excuse me. Sorry.
借过，对不起，抱歉
-That's not right. -No?
- 这个不对 - 不对？
You're right about DonaId and me, but-- HoId this, okay?
我和唐诺的事你说得对… 不过，你替我拿一下
Oh, sure.
当然
Hi, Kent.
嗨，肯特
Hi. How you doing?
嗨，你好吗？
I'm sorry. I'm going nuts. Thanks.
对不起，我竟然弄错了 谢谢
-CIark. -Yeah.
- 克拉克 - 是
Lana.
拉娜！
BRAD: Hey, sweet.
哦，甜心
Here I am.
我来了
Remember when you were prom queen? AII these guys were wa ting for a dance?
记得你当选为舞会皇后 一票人等着要和你跳舞
There's on y one guy on your dance card now. Huh, honey?
现在只剩下一个人了
-That's good oId-- -Brad W son.
- 真是美好的… - 布莱德威尔逊
-Hi, Brad. -Hi, Kent.
- 嗨，布莱德 - 嗨，肯特
Long time no see.
好久不见
You know, see, see, see?
你懂吧，不见？
-Come on, Lana. -No, I can't .
- 来吧！拉娜 - 不行
-CIark aIready asked me. -I did?
克拉克他先请我的
Lana, I haven't danced--
拉娜，我好久没跳…
Ah, Gorman. Another week, another check.
高曼 又一星期又一张支票
Don't you have another one for me? I put in a voucherfor expenses.
你有没有另外一张支票要给我？ 我申请了公费
What?
什么？
Yeah, yeah.
有
Here you go.
拿去
Thanks for heIping me out.
谢谢你帮我收拾
You kidding? A ot of guys wouId Iike to be where I am.
你别客气，拉娜 很多人羡慕我有机会帮你
You'd be surprised at how many offers I didn't get.
你会讶异我根本没有成觉到 甚至布莱德都不会留下
It reaIIy isn't easy.
- 真是不容易 - 这些长幡？你只要…
No, not the streamers. Everything.
不是这些长幡，是全部的
Not that I'm compIaining. It's just that...
不是我要抱怨 只是…
...I don't know why, I just feeI I ke I can taIk to you.
我不知道为什么 我觉得我可以和你谈心
What?
什么？
I fee Iike I can taIk to you!
我觉得我可以和你谈心！
-You can? -Yes.
- 是吗？ - 是的
-You know something, Lana? -What?
- 你知道吗，拉娜？ - 什么？
I aIways....
我一直…
I aIways wished that you wou d.
我一直希望你会
I mean, even back in high schooI.
甚至在高中时代
-Remember when you were--? -Queen of the prom.
- 记得你是… - 舞会皇后
Then three years after the royaI wedding, the king abdicated.
经过三年的婚姻 他退出了
-Isn't that terrib e? -Yeah, sure is.
这是不是太糟了吗？
You know what the probIem is?
你知道问题所在吗？
I don't know, too much mayonnaise?
不知道，是太多美乃滋了吗？
Dona d oved mayonnaise. Why wouId that be the probIem?
唐诺喜欢吃美乃滋 这不会有问题的
No, the probIem is, why do I stay in SmaIIv I e?
问题是为什么我要留在小镇？
BeI eve me, I've asked myseIf that.
相信我，我一直这样自问
Do you know how Iucky you are to Iive in MetropoIis? The B g Apricot.
你知道你有多幸运能住在大都会？ 人人向往的地方
WeII, Lana, you couId--
- 那你可以… - 说来容易，我不能不顾瑞奇
-Ricky? -My IittIe boy.
- 瑞奇？ - 我儿子
-You? Oh, that's great. -Yeah.
- 你的，这不错 - 是
I mean, at east here we have a house and I've got a job that pays the biIIs.
在这里，我们有一栋房子 我有工作可以支付帐单
Except for Iast winter when the fueI biIIs kept going up and up.
但是去年冬天开始 燃料帐单就变得越来越贵
Yeah. Even had to pawn my diamond ring then.
我甚至把结婚钻戒拿去当了
That's a shame.
那真可惜
You never got married?
你还没有结婚吗？
-Me? -Yeah.
- 我吗？ - 是啊
WeII, I was--
我…
No. Not....
还没
You know, years Iater you can Iook at someone and think:
你知道吗？ 几年后再看到某人就会想…
''WeII, I guess that's the one that got away."
我想，那就是我错过的机会
Give me that again, oId buddy. Run t by me just one more time.
再说一次 我要再听一次
-E ghty-five thousand doIIars. -Missing?
- 八万五千元 - 不见了
EmbezzIed, Mr. Webster. StoIen from the firm.
一笔完整的钱 从公司中被侵占
VERA: By whom?
谁干的？
That's what I want to know. By whom? Whom?
我要知道是谁干的？
WEBSTER: Vera, get ahoId of yourseIf.
佛莅，控制一下自己吧！
Nobody eIse ever wiII.
从未有人敢如此做
SIMPSON: I don't know.
我不知道
Whom?
是谁呢？
In the oId days it was simpIe.
在往日事情简单得多
We kept books, we knew what was go ng in and what was paid out.
我们有帐簿，有收据 哪一笔帐出去，哪一笔帐进来
If somebody wanted to rob you...
即使有人要抢钱
...they'd come in w th a gun and say, "Stick them up."
他们都带着枪进来说 把钱装进去
Now they get bIasted computers to do their dirty work.
现在这些人利用后杂的电脑 做这种下流事情
My oId friend, you are yesterday.
我的老朋友，你成为老古董了
Whoever puIIed this caper is tomorrow.
至于谁做了此事 将会是明日之星
Mr. Webster, it's time for your massage.
维斯伯先生 该是你按摩的时候了
Does th s woman have the right to burst in--?
这种女人怎能突然闯进来
Now, now, Vera. Simpson, you know my psychic nutritionist?
等等，佛莅 辛普森，这位是我物理治疗师
-He o. -We are trying to hoId a meet ng here.
- 哈罗 - 抱歉，我们正要在此闻会
Why don't you ho d your breath instead. Maybe you'lI turn bIue.
你为何不省省力别讲话 这样很容易血压上升
-Improvement. -I'm about to take a human Iife.
- 没水准 - 注意，我正要取你的人命
Simpson, wouId you excuse us for a second, pIease?
辛普森 请你回避几分钟好吗？
-Mouths cIosed. Ears open. -She's a big pig.
- 闭嘴，用耳听 - 她是一只大肥猪
I can't have anyone with me who isn't with me.
我不容许不服从我的人 和我一起
Now, girIs.
好了，女孩们
Simpson.
辛普森
WeII, o d chum. What now?
老朋友，现在该如何呢？
Kiss the 85 thou goodbye?
就让八万五千块飞走吗？
Keep on paying the thief his saIary untiI he shakes the money tree again?
持续让他得手 以为这是摇钱树吗？
-He's bound to sI p up sooner or Iater. -Why?
- 他迟早会露出马脚的 - 为什么？
That's what they aIways say in the mov es.
我也不知道 在电影中常是这样演的
He won't sIip up at aII. No, not at aII.
他不会不露马脚的 不会的
He'II keep quietIy taking the bread from our mouths.
他一定会继续从我的口中 不断地偷食我的面包
He'lI keep a Iow profiIe and won't do a thing to ca attention to himseIf.
他一定会不断地做 越陷越深露出马脚
UnIess, of course, he s a compIete and utter moron.
当然 除非他真是一位天才罪犯
BOY 1 : I'II go f rst. Andrew.
我先选，安德鲁
BOY 2: I'lI pick Chris. LANA: You feeI good? You feeI ready?
- 我选克立思 - 你准备好了吗？
LANA Ricky, your shoe.
瑞奇，你的球鞋
-You mean, we've gotta take Ricky? -You guys Iost the toss.
- 我们要和瑞奇一组吗？ - 你们猜拳输了
AII right, come on, Ricky.
好吧，瑞奇
LANA: Wa t, wait-- -Come on, good Iuck.
- 等等 - 祝好运
-I just can't stand this. -Oh, Lana. It'lI be okay.
- 我真受不了这样 - 拉娜，没事的，相信我
I know, I was a Iate bIoomer myseIf.
我自己也是大器晚成
It's not just that he's sma I, he's the onIy kid in town wthout a father.
我不是因为他年纪小 他是镇上唯一没父亲的小孩
Oh, Iook. He's stewed to the giIIs in the midd e of the afternoon.
看看 才下午就醉醺醺了
-Gee, aI he had was chocoIate miIk. -No, him.
- 我只喝了巧克力牛奶 - 不，我是指他
Hey, sweet thing.
甜心
L ttIe k d getting hass ed, huh?
小朋友在比赛了
-Kent, you stiII here? -I seem to be, Brad.
- 肯特，你也在这儿？ - 是啊，布莱德
AII he needs s a few pointers from the oId champ here.
他只需要有冠军经验的人 指导一下就好了
I won the aII-country bowIing trophy two years in a row.
我参加了两年的 全国保龄球巡回比赛
I didn't know that.
这我还不知道
Yeah. NaturaI athIete can pIay any sport.
天生有运动细胞的人 什么运动都会
Brad, you're just gonna make it worse.
布莱德，你只会搞砸
-It's aII right. It'II be okay. -He'lI make t worse.
- 没关系，没事的 - 克拉克，他会搞砸的
You watch, he'II get a spare.
你看着，他会补进的
Come on, R cky.
加油，瑞奇
Hey, kid, you're hoIding it aII wrong.
孩子，你球拿错了
-Let oId Brad show you how it's done. -Brad.
- 让我示范一次给你看 - 布莱德
Excuse me. Say, Brad, I think maybe he'lI be better off doing t his way.
对不起，布莱德 我想最好还是让孩子他自己打
For a guy Iucky to be waterboy, you've got a big mouth.
你这种不入流的人 话还真多
I don't think he needs a esson in front of the other kids.
我只想说瑞奇不会希望 在同伴面前，被指导如何打球
-He needs a man to show him. -He's doing just fine. Excuse me.
- 他需要有人教他 - 他会没事的，抱歉
Here you go, Rcky.
去吧！瑞奇
And g ve it your best shot. Okay? There you go.
尽全力，好吗？去吧
Sorry.
抱歉
Gesundheit.
保重啊！
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, Gus, the boss wants to see you.
格斯，老板要见你
He can see me aII right. HeIIo, Mr. Lewis.
他一直在看着我 你好吗？老板
No, not that boss. The boss.
不是那位老板，是大老板
-You mean, the boss... -Yup.
你是说大老板
-...wants to see me?
要见我？
Oh, my God, why wouId he wanna see me?
他要见我干什么？
I mean....
我是说…
Why wouId the boss wanna see me?
老板要见我干什么？
There's no reason.
没有原因吗？
Then why'd he--? Oh, I know!
那为何他…？我知道了！
It's my suggestion for the voIIeybaII un forms.
一定是关于 我对排球制服的意见
That's it.
就是这样
Ross the boss. Ross the boss. The boss!
罗斯老板…老板！
Be caIm. Be cooI. Be coI ected.
冷静，镇静，要坦然
Mr. Webster? Mr. Webster?
维斯伯先生…？
Mr. Webster, I did not-- Mr. Webster.
维斯伯先生，我…维斯伯先生
WEBSTER: Mr. August Gorman?
格斯高曼先生吗？
GUS: August Gorman here.
先生，我就是高曼
I know you're a man of compassion, and I don't wanna go to jaiI...
我知道你心肠很好 我不要坐牢
...because they have robbers and rapists--
因为他们那里有 强盗犯、强奸犯
I just wanna ask you one question.
我只是要问你一个问题
You've been a naughty guy, haven't you?
你是一个很顽皮的人 是吗？
Come on, adm t it now.
说良心话吧！
You've been just a ittIe bit naughty, haven't you?
你在工作上常有一点顽皮 是吗？
-I was kind of-- -That's aII right. I understand.
- 我是那一种… - 好了，不用多说
I can-- What do the young fo ks say today?
我可以了解年轻人 现在的心态
''Dig where you're coming from, brother."
梦想出人头地的心情，兄弟
-You wanna be rich, right? -How, wha--
你想要发财，是吗？
I was born rich. Never worn the same pa r of socks tw ce.
我一出生便注定富有 从不重后穿同一双袜子
GUS: What do you do with your socks?
那你怎样处理那些袜子？
I don't know. They're Iaundered and sent to some charitable institution, I think.
拿去洗了“巴 送给慈济了吧
ActuaIIy, I don't know. Maybe they turn them into dust rags...
我不知道或许变成别的了
...or pen-wipers or something.
或许是立可白
Or maybe socks.
或许是袜子
Yes! That never occurred to me.
是的！我从不管这些
Gus, you know something? You're a genius.
格斯 你知道你的确是一位天才
A naughty genius, but what the heII? Nobody's perfect, right? Cheers.
一位顽皮的天才，但又如何 没有人是十全十美的，干杯
Because of the ha f-cent thing with the computers.
是因为我用电脑 把半毛钱转出来的事
No, no, because computers ruIe the worId today.
不…是因为电脑控制了 今日整个世界
The feIIow that can fooI the computers can ruIe the worId h mseIf.
而控制电脑的人可以控制世界
I've been searching for somebody who can make these mach nes...
我一直都在物色一位 能成功地利用电脑的人
...do what they're not supposed to. Get my drift?
做人所不能的事 你明白我的意思吗？
GUS: Yes! -Gus...
- 明白！ - 格斯…
...Webscoe, the Webscoe industriaI compIex, is a famiIy-owned carteI.
维斯寇集团，维斯寇工业 是一个家族的大企业
Some magnesium here, some z nc there.
有些是要探测镁矿 有些要找锌矿
RaiIroads, farm machinery. You foIIow me?
铁路，农业机械 你在听吗？
GUS: I foIIow you, sir.
我在听
-Gus, do you know what I want now? -No.
- 格斯，你知道我想要什么吗？ - 不知道
I want coffee.
我要咖啡
AII rght. BIack, cream, sugar, or--?
需要奶、糖，还是…？
No, you don't seem to understand.
不是，你似乎不明白
Under different company names, I controI the price of coffee beans...
众多不同的公司品牌 我要控制咖啡的价格
...in VenezueIa, BraziI, BoI via, Jamaica and the RepubIic of Gabon.
在委内瑞拉、巴西、玻利维亚 牙买加、加彭共和国
But I've got a probIem and I think maybe you can heIp me.
但是，我现在有一个问题 你大概可以帮我解决
One country won't pIay baII with me. You know how that can bug a guy, rght?
就是有一个国家不赏我的脸 我想你知道这有多丢脸
That couId bug-- What country?
不赏脸… 那个国家？
-CoIomb a. -CoIomb a?
哥伦比亚
CoIombia has two mportant exports, and one of them's coffee.
哥国是极重要的 咖啡进出口国家
And I've tried to reason w th them. BeIieve me, I've tried.
我试过多次 相信我，我真的试过多次
But this one miserabIe, pissant IittIe country...
但这真是令人难过的 固执国家
...has the gaII to th nk it can dictate the economy of an open market. Gus.
以为可以阻碍了我的目标 不让我独占这个市场，格斯…
Gus, my friend...
格斯，我的朋友
...we're going to teach them a Iesson, aren't we?
- 我们要给他们一个教训，对吗？ - 维斯伯先生…
Destroy the entire CoIombian coffee crop...
毁掉哥伦比亚所有的咖啡田
...right down to the Iast bean.
令他们成为不毛之地
-The Iast bean, we are. -Right.
- 不毛之地？我们？ - 没错
But you got so much. You know, Iike--
但你拥有这么多了…
A wise man once said, I think it was AttiIa the Hun:
你知道为什么有人曾说 我想说的人真是独具慧眼
''lt is not enough that I succeed.
成功还不足够
Everyone eIse must faiI."
必须其他人都失败
Seems fa r.
有道理
-Gus. -What?
- 格斯 - 什么？
You are going to do this for me.
你要为我做这件事
-How? -The weather.
- 怎么做？ - 利用天气
You d dn't say your mother was here.
你没有告诉我你妈妈会来
I'm his sister. His baby sister.
我是他的妹妹，他最小的妹妹
Gus, teII me, have you ever heard of VuIcan?
格斯，告诉我 难道你从未听过华根吗？
Hi, Ms. VuIcan.
嗨，华根小姐
VuIcan is the weather sate te our government put up...
华根是气象卫星 是政府设在…
...to mon tor the weather.
运行轨道中 监视气象变化用的
But if somebody were to reprogram it, it couId do much more.
但如果有人能重新输入程式 它便能发挥更大的功效
It couId make weather.
可以制造天气的变化
WEBSTER: Storms and fIoods.
风暴或洪水
VERA: BIizzards, heat waves.
暴风雪、热浪
How do you do that?
要怎么做？
Like everyth ng e se in the 20th century, Gus.
就像二十世纪 每一件事的作法一样
You push buttons.
你只要用按按几个键就行了
-There you go. -It's the f rst time I won anything.
- 好了 - 这是我一生中第一次赢得东西
You won my hand, Maury.
你赢得我的芳心，莫瑞
But this s the first time I won anything vaIuab e.
对，但这是我第一次 赢得有价值的东西
Let's get one wth the sombreros.
戴上草帽会更像样
Mr. White, you'II be in this, handing them the r pIane tickets.
怀特先生 你过来把机票交给他们
-Why do I have to do this?
- 为什么总要我做这种事？
You're Iucky I d dn't fire you. I get a chance at exc usive photos...
你，你没被开除算运气好 本来有独家的…
...of history's biggest factory fire.
史上最大化学工厂火灾的照片
He comes home with a broken Ieg and 12 meIted roIIs of fiIm.
回来时腿断了 照片也熔化了
It was hot.
因为热度太高
SmiIe, Mr. White.
笑一笑，怀特先生
South America! I can't beIieve my Iuck!
南美洲，我不敢相信我的运气
See, f you don't want them to trace it back...
注意，你想要做但不被人发现…
...you've gotta punch in to some IittIe rinky-dink outfit...
得找个隐密不引人注意的基地 装置一台电脑
...that has a IittIe Mickey Mouse computer--
一台小但功能多的电脑就行
SomepIace you can sneak nto, rght?
你可以藏身的地方，是吗？
Somebody couId--
有人可以”"'
SomepIace where nobody knows him so they can't connect him with us.
那个地方没有人认识他 他们此不会怀疑他和我们有关
Webscoe has 1 12 subsidiaries.
维斯寇集团有112家子公司
They're aII I nked into the centraI computer system.
所有电脑系统都和中央电脑连线
How about somepIace...
要找一个…这种地方
...smaII?
小地方？
DRIVER: SmaIIviIIe. Th s is SmaIIviIIe. We' have a five-minute stop here.
小镇，小镇到了 停留五分钟
Mind your step.
小心走路
Watch your step, pIease.
小，。楼梯
Thanks, SeIma.
谢谢！席玛
Thanks a Iot. Lana. Have a good day, now.
再见！拉娜 一天・险快
CLARK: Let me heIp you, Lana.
让我帮你，拉娜
I'm sorry.
对不起
-Thanks, CIark. -Sit down, Buster. Good boy.
- 谢谢，克拉克 - 你去坐下，巴士达，乖
RICKY: Come on, Buster, sit down. That's a good boy.
坐下，巴士达，别乱动，乖
CLARK: Okay. You aII set? Great.
你们都好了吗？很好
MAN: I'm not saying another word.
我不再多说了
That's it. Okay?
就这样
Jesus Chrst!
天呀！
Don't they have picn cs in Metropo is, Mr. Kent?
你们在大都会也有郊游吗？ 肯特先生
WeII, not quite Iike this, Ricky.
有，只是和这里的不大一样
-Mom and I do this aII the time. -You do?
- 妈妈和我常一块出来郊游 - 真的！
-I'II heIp you. -Stay cIose by and be carefuI, okay?
- 我帮你 - 瑞奇，别走远，要小心，好吗？
Okay, Mom.
好的，妈妈
RICKY: Come on, Buster. Let's find you a rabb t. Come on. Rabbit.
来，巴士达，去找兔子 来，巴士达
-This s so nice for him. -Here you go.
这样对他来说太好了
It's even nicer when there's a man around, which sn't that often.
难得有一位男性在他身边 这对他的成长较好
-There's a ot of cho ces. -The good ones are married.
- 还有好多的选择机会 - 不，所有好的男人都结婚了
That's why Brad thinks he's God's gift to women.
所以布莱德以为 他是上帝给女人的礼物
He won't take no for an answer, but he's the onIy one asking.
他不接受拒绝 但只有他自己在要求
No, Lana, I meant there's a ot of cho ces here.
不，拉娜 我还是觉得有很多选择的
This is rea y qu te some picnic. There's ...
这真是不错的郊游 有这种…
...some of that.
这个
Green stuff.
绿东西
Hey, pate.
豆泥
Boy, th s pate is reaIIy unusuaI.
这种豆泥味道真特别
I didn't make any-- Oh, C ark.
我没有弄
That's Buster's dog food.
这是巴士达的狗食物
-It's good. -Don't eat it!
- 蛮好吃的啊 - 别再吃了
What time's the dog eat?
小狗什么时候吃？
-This is nice. -Here.
- 真不错 - 拿去
It's aII right, Lana.
没关系的，拉娜
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, where you go ng? Come on!
你去那里？回来！巴士达
Buster, stop messing about!
巴士达，不要闹了！
-How much Ionger--? -I was just thinking--
- 要待多久…？ - 我正在想…
-I'm sorry. No, go ahead. -No. You.
- 抱歉，请说 - 你说
WeII...
我只是在想…
...I was just thinking that...
我在想，像你这样的人
...somebody Iike you couId do reaI y weII in Metropo is.
一定可以在大都会发展
I suppose I have to face it. I'm not gonna f nd what I want in Sma viIIe anymore.
我想我非得如此了 小镇里没有我要的了
Cou d I make it n MetropoIis? What wouId I do when I got there?
我可以在大都会过活吗？ 我能做什么工作？
CaII me.
打电话给我
-No, I wouIdn't wanna caII you. -You don't wanna caII me?
- 不，我不想打给你 - 你不想打给我？
Yes, I wanna caII you, but I wouIdn't wanna be a nuisance to you.
我想打给你 但我不想为你增加麻烦
I don't think you couId ever be a nuisance to me, Lana.
我从未想过你会为我增加麻烦
C ark, may I teII you something?
克拉克，我可以告诉你件事吗？
My oiI pan is Ieaking.
我油箱正在漏油
See? There's something dripping.
看，有东西在漏
-Can I give you a hand? -No, thanks.
- 我可以帮上忙吗？ - 不用，谢谢
With a the car troubIe I have, I studied up on auto repair.
由于车子太烂 我必须学会怎样修理车子
Look at this.
看看这个
CLARK: Oh, boy.
天啊
Lana, I think I'II just go see if Ricky's aII rght. You okay?
拉娜，我去看看瑞奇怎样了 你没事吧？
Yeah.
嗯
FARMER: Gosh, is he a rght?
天啊，他没事吧？
Hi.
嗨！
Superman?
超人？
That's me.
就是我
RICKY: Mom! Mom!
妈！妈！
There you go. He's aII right, but have a doctor check h m.
到了，他没事，女士 但最好还是给医生看看
Thank you.
谢谢
-I'm Lana Lang. This is Ricky. -Nice to meet you.
- 我是蓝拉娜，他是瑞奇 - 很高兴认识你们
And this s C ark.
- 瑞奇 - 这是克拉克
I reaIIy have to be going. So ong, R cky. Bye.
我真的要走了 再见瑞奇
We were fIying, Mom!
妈，我们在天空飞！
What were you doing, anyway?
你究竟在做什么？
I was Iooking for Buster.
我在找巴士达
-Buster! Buster! CLARK: I found him!
- 巴士达！巴士达！ - 我找到他了
CLARK: Come on, boy. That's it.
好了，就这样
Mr. Kent, Superman was here!
肯特先生，超人刚在这里
-What? -Yes, he reaIIy was.
- 什么？ - 是的，他真的在这儿
Aren't you excited?
你不觉得很兴奋吗？
I'm from MetropoIis. I see Superman every day.
我在大都会的时候 我每天看到他
You do? CouId you get me his autograph?
真的！你可否给我 他的亲笔签名
I don't know. If had a nickeI for every time some ittIe kid....
我不知道 我需要打个电话给他…
Yeah? What do you want?
是的…你要干什么？
We're in big troubIe, aren't we?
我们有麻烦了，不是吗？
-What? -We're in big troubIe.
- 什么？ - 我说我们麻烦大了…
First, they ost the invoice.
首先是丢掉了所有的收据
When they found it, they reaIized they came up short on a few items.
然后他们又找到了 却少了几项东西
So I rented a car because I missed the pIane from CIeveIand. 4:00, you know.
所以我必须要租车 我错过四点到克里夫兰的飞机
And a fIat tire on the highway. What a kicker.
在路上又爆胎了 真・廖
Had to fix it myseIf with these IittIe p nkies.
我必须自己去处理这些
And I figured your boss was gonna be reaI peeved, you know what I mean?
而我想你的老板真的会气死 你懂吗？
What do you mean?
你在说些什么？
He is going to hang our butts against the waII.
他将会把我们钉在墙上
He wanted this specia order instaIIed...
他要这个特殊订购
...in his office no Iater than tomorrow morning.
明天早上以前在他办公室装好
Let me in because I gotta set it up tonight.
所以你必须让我进去 因为我今晚就得安装
Get a I what set up?
要安装什么？
PaI, you are a rea Iifesaver. I mean, a reaI Iifesaver.
兄弟，你真的是救世主 你真的是救世主
-Which way's the off ce? -Straight on ahead.
- 办公室怎么去？ - 直走
-FoIIow me. -I'm right behind you.
- 跟我走 - 我就在你身后
Oh, yeah.
好耶
BRAD: Not bad. It's pretty good.
有些不错…很好…
You know what's wrong with this Singapore wing?
你知道新加坡的翼酒 有什么不好吗？
GUS: SIing! S ngapore SIing.
滑酒，是新加坡滑酒
What's wrong with t?
有什么不对吗？
There's not enough vodka in it.
这里面的伏特加不够
There's no vodka in it!
这里面没有伏特加
What did I teII you? Put some vodka in it.
这就是我要告诉你的 加些伏特加进去
What did you--? You know.
这是你要的，你知道的
-Yeah. -There's vodka in it now, buddy.
现在这里面有伏特加了
Yeah, perfect.
对…太好了
-You never do pass out, do you? -Nope.
- 你从未喝昏过吧？ - 没有…
Never.
从未！
Job we done, buddy.
做得好，兄弟
You thought I was drunk too, didn't you? Ha, ha.
你以为我也喝醉了 是吗？
Foo ed you.
骗到你了
Get the keys, get the keys.
把钥匙给我…
Somebody's drunk.
有人喝醉了
HeIIo, baby!
哈罗宝贝…！
How's the ittIe baby?
哈罗，小宝贝
Okay.
好了
AII rght, et's get down to it. Let's do it.
好…好了…开始干活吧
One, two, button your shoe.
1…2…按钮…
"Both keys at the same time"?
两把钥匙要同时插
Wait. Wait a minute.
等…等一下
Think you've won, don't you?
你以为你赢了？
The PhiIIy FIash!
戏法人人会变…
Okay, ready?
好，准备好？
One, two, three!
1、2、3 !
Yeah. Now we' see what we'II see.
现在我们看看有什么
Come on, pIease.
快，拜托
There it is!
就这样
He o! Now...
现在，哈罗！
...getting down to bus ness.
开始做事了
I am a genius.
我是天才！
I am a....
我是…
Longitude...
经度…
...and the other thing. Latitude, rght?
还有其他的纬度，对吧？
Oh, Iook, Maury. A native wedding.
你看，莫瑞 当地的婚礼仪式
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
（西班牙文）
No one said at the Dally Planet that this was the rainy season!
没有一个同事 告诉我们现在是雨季
NEWSCASTER: Meteorologists are baffled by the tornado and ralnstorms...
气象学者非常地疑惑 飓风加上猛烈的大雨
...that struck the country of Colombia this afternoon...
今天下午肆虐南美洲的哥伦比亚
...threatening to destroy the nation's entlre coffae crop for the next flve years.
完全摧毁咖啡田 影响未来五年咖啡的生产
Gale-force wlnds up to...
瞬问强风…
...an incredibIe 250 miIes an hour Iashed the countryside...
高达时速250哩 冲击到所有村庄
...whiIe 12 inches of rainfa have aIready been recorded in just one day.
同时在当天雨量达12英寸
A spokesman for the Department of Meteorology said this was, l quote.;
我引述 气象局发官人的话
"The most awesome dispIay of natural forcas slnce Noah's ark.''
这是最可怕的自然力量…
If I Iaugh any harder, I' I spIit my s des!
我再笑下去我会歪一边
--to dafy all laws of weather systems known to science.
气象似乎已经违背了 所有的理论
What a shame.
真可惜！
Poor Iitt e CoIombia. WeII....
可怜的哥伦比亚！
I'm gonna get you for that, you big s y!
你真淘气 你这个大笨蛋
Bubba, do you reaIize what we're on to?
老哥，你真的了解我们在干嘛吗？
WEBSTER: Do I?
了解吗？
Every time a drunk sobers up, he'II dr nk Webster coffee.
以后所有人喝的咖啡 就是维斯伯咖啡
Why stop at coffee?
为何要选咖啡？
A cup of coffee gets the word off to work n the morning.
一杯咖啡就可以让全世界 早上出门去上班
But what keeps the worId working?
但又是什么让世界运作？
Diet soda?
低糖汽水？
Vera, you mean...? You mean--?
佛莅，你是说？你是说？
Today, coffee.
今天是咖啡
Tomorrow, the oiI!
明天此是石油！
-OiI? -If Gus can push the right buttons--
- 石油？ - 如果高曼可以正确地运用
I can have it aI . HoIy cats!
我就可以控制全世界的石油 天啊！
AII the oiI.
所有的石油
AII the pumps.
所有的油井
AII the tankers.
所有的油槽
This is some nifty idea, Vera.
这真是个不错的主意，佛莅
GUS: Boss? WEBSTER: Very nifty.
- 老板 - 非常不错
-Just the man I want to see. -Boss, t is not my fauIt.
- 我正好要找你 - 老板…这不是我的错
Isn't it neat? There--
干得是不是很好…
-What's not your fau t? -Superman.
- 什么不是你的错？ - 超人…
How was I to know he was gonna start doing his th ng...
我怎么知道 他会阻扰你的事情
...when you started doing your thing?
当你要这样做呢？
VERA: What are you taIking about? -What am taIk--?
- 你在说什么？ - 我在说什么…
It was just on teIevision, man. Didn't you see it?
就是电视上播的，老兄 你没看到吗？
Don't caII me ''man.''
别叫我老兄！
I just saw CoIombia bite the dust. That's aII.
我看到哥伦比亚被毁了
You d dn't see the man come f ying out of the sky from the c ouds? It was h m!
你没看到他从云端飞出来吗？ 就是他
With h s cape fIapping in the--
他的斗蓬飞扬，然后…
His cape was fIapp ng in the wind!
他的斗蓬就是在飞扬
He was fIying! He was great!
他在飞翔，真棒
He was just fIying around....
就这样飞
His cape was blowing ln the wlnd llke thls. lt looked like a flag!
就像这样穿过云层 就这样地飞
And he Ianded right in the middIe of this big pIantation!
然后他就降落在大农场的中问
And he checked everything out wth his x-ray vision.
他就先用透视眼检查了状况
And then he put these Iaser beams out of his eyes onto everything.
然后他用雷射眼 修后所有的东西
Straight-out Iasar points.
用雷射修复
Drled up everythlngl
把所有的东西都弄干了
Just Iike that!
就在一瞬问！
I'm taIk ng about dry ng it up. Iike machines in the men's rooms.
就像在厕所的烘手机一样
You know what I mean?
你知道我在说什么吧？
Hot air comes out when you put your hands under.
手放在下面热空气会出来 你可把手烘干
Sometimes they don't work, right?
有时是没用
But Superman's worked!
而超人办到了
You think he stood around to take bows? Not th s man.
你以为他在开玩笑吗？ 这家伙不是
No, sir. He fI es off again. R ght?
没有，他又飞走
Then he saw what rea y caused the troub e.
然后他看到了问题的所在
He flew into the tornado ...
他就飞向龙卷风
...went down to the bottom of it, and turned it upside down!
从下面往上雅 他就把事情解决了
He made the little end on top and the big and on the bottom!
他使得龙卷风反转了
I was gonna go crazy!
我快要疯了！
I've never seen nothing ike it.
我从来没看过那样的东西
The big end was on the bottom.
把龙卷风阻止了…
L ttIe end on the top.
上下颠倒了
Mr. Ross, it was-- The b g....
罗斯先生…它说…很大…
Superman's bad.
超人太坏了！
I'II say he was.
我说他是
I mean, he was bad!
我是说他很坏！
No.
不…
No!
不！
Here, et me heIp.
甜心，我来，我来帮你
-It was a perfect pIan. It was fooIproof! -And we were the fooIs.
- 完美的计划要有傻子愿意执行 - 而我们就是那种傻子
It's not my fauIt. I did what I was supposed to do.
这不是我的错，我尽到本分了
He ruined it. That ousy do-gooder ru ned it.
他破坏的！ 是个差劲的好人破坏的
Now that he's puIIed off this stunt, he'l try and ruin my oiI scheme too.
现在他或许会破坏到 我的石油计划
-I've got to get rid of him. -How?
- 我必须要除掉他 - 要怎么做？
Shoot h m? You know about him and buIIets.
开枪射他？ 你知道他对子弹的承受度
-Kryptonite. -What?
- 氪石 - 什么？
Or krypton-ham, or krypton-heimer?
气火子…还是气豆子？
I forget what you ca it, but it's stuff that can hurt Superman.
我不知道要怎么叫它 但是这玩意儿会干掉超人
-How wouId you know about that? -I know a few th ngs.
- 你怎么会知道的？ - 我还是知道一些事情
I know, from the graff ti I saw.
我知道了，从漫画书看到的
WEBSTER: Wait a second.
等一下…
She's right.
她是对的
Kryptonite. I remember reading about t in an interview with him.
氪石！我记得有一篇采访中 有提到这样东西
VERA: Where does it come from?
它是哪里来的？
WEBSTER: The same pIanet Superman came from: Krypton.
从超人来的星球上有氪石
VERA: Where is Krypton?
哪里找得到氮石？
GUS: It's nowhere.
找不到的
It bIew up in space, years ago.
那星球几年前说炸掉了
They sent Superman here from there when he was just a baby.
- 他们在超人小时候，就送他来地球了 - 对！
I know some things too.
你看我知道一些吧！
Wait a minute. You know what happens when a pIanet expIodes.
等一下…你知道一个星球爆炸 会如何吗？
-Debris. Th ngs fIoating in space. VERA: So?
- 残骸，东西会飘到太空中 - 怎样？
So aII we have to do is find out where in heaven Krypton used to be.
所以我们只要 找到氪石就行了
Then we get good oId Gus to contact the VuIcan sateIIite.
那我们只要让格斯在这里 用卫星去找就可以了
OId Gus has been doing some thinking.
格斯已经在思考这些了
Good. That's why I keep you around.
很好，这就是我要你办事的原因
Yeah. I've been thinking that I'm not making enough money for this g g.
是…我是在想我没有得到应有的报酬
Gus, if there's anything I hate...
格斯，我平生最痛恨的…
...it's greed.
就是贪婪
Greed? Mr. Ross, just a minute.
贪婪？罗斯先生，等一下
Let me teII you something.
我要说的是…
I can't ski!
我不会滑雪！
WEBSTER: Once Gus contacts the Vulcan satelllta...
一旦格斯和华根卫星连上线
...he orders lt to search through spaca...
就可以命令搜寻外太空
...around where Krypton went bya-bye.
就可以找到氮石失落之处了
Then the laser probe locks on to a floating chunk of Kryptonita.
然后卫星很容易就可以找到氪石
The computer analyzes the components...
由电脑分析成分后
...and the boys at the lab dupllcate tha stuff down hera.
我们此可以在实验室里复制
GUS: "Unknown"?
未知？
What the heII, he ain't gonna smoke it.
管他的，他又不会去吸它
SECRETARY: Mr. White can't be responsibIe.
怀特先生无法对此事负责
Where is he?
他在哪里？
PIease, Mr. Stokis.
拜托啦，两位
He'lI pay for this.
他要付出代价
Get out your waIIet!
准备付钱吧，怀特先生
PERRY: Good morning. STOKIS: Don't you "good morning" me.
- 早安！ - 别向我问早安！
"OId, oId reIationships suddenIy seem very much the same.
往日关系依旧
The prettiest gir in the schooI--''
学校中最美的女孩
--is st the prettiest girI n the schoo .
仍然是学校中最美的女孩
-HeIIo? LANA: Hello. Oh, hl, Clark.
- 哈罗？ - 哈罗，嗨，克拉克
Lana! H , I was just thinking about you.
拉娜！嗨 我正在想你
Listen, I have a probIem with Ricky.
听着，瑞奇有些麻烦
Why? What happened to Ricky?
什么事情？瑞奇怎么了？
It's Superman's autograph you got him. He got carried away...
就是你给他超人的签名 他真的很高兴
...and toId the k ds Superman was coming on his birthday.
就告诉其他的孩子 超人会参加他下星期三的生日
Okay, it was wrong...
好，我知道这样不好
...but when Wednesday comes and Superman doesn't show, it's gonna....
但是… 如果星期三超人没有来…
WeII, Lana, in this case I th nk I can go ahead and speak for Superman.
拉娜，这种情况 我想我可以去跟超人讲一下
I mean, he and I are pretty cIose, you know.
我是说 他和我相当熟识
And you can te Ricky that Superman wiII be there on Wednesday, aII right?
你告诉瑞奇 超人下星期三会到的，好吗？
WeII, he's gonna get the best home-cooked meaI he's had...
他会尝到最道地的家乡菜 他会…
... n a Iong time.
垂涎三尺
-Tell Superman we thlnk ha's wonderful. -A rght.
- 你告诉超人，我们觉得他很好 - 好
-But, CIark... -Yeah?
- 但是，克拉克… - 怎样？
...you're the best.
你是最好的
And I'II take it to the Supreme Court f I have to.
就算我要告到最高法院 也在所不惜
But it wasn't our fauIt. It was an act of God.
但是这不是我们的错 这是上帝的意思！
In a church?
在教堂里？
SC ENTIST: Hey!
嘿！
Here's that compound you ordered.
这是你要的组合物
Can't imagine what you want with it.
我无法想像这是什么
But you got it.
但是你可以拿去了
What the heII am I afraid for? I'm from Earth.
我在怕什么鬼？ 我是地球人耶
SUPERMAN: Lana, I reaIIy wasn't expect ng a this.
拉娜，我真的不知道会这样
I guess they did get a ttIe carried away.
我想他们真的想做一些事
Superman, we aI know...
超人，我们都知道
...that you're not ooking for honors and awards.
你并不期望被表扬
But when we heard that you were coming to see your paI Ricky...
但是当我们听到你要来此 找你的好友瑞奇
...we reaIized that this was our chance to say thank you.
我们此想这是 我们向你说谢谢的好机会
First, for putting out the Lake Comooga fire.
首先是扑灭化学厂的大火
And not east, for saving IittIe R cky.
还有你救了瑞奇一命
So since you aIready have the key to our hearts...
既然你已经 在我们的心中占有一席之地
...Superman...
超人…
...may I present you with the key to the city.
容许我在此向你献上市钥
Thank you, s r.
谢谢
As you were.
你们都在
Now Iisten up.
现在听好
I just came in d rectIy...
我刚刚
...from the Pentagon...
从五角大厦过来
...and you better beIieve there's a damn good reason that I did.
你们最好相信我来此的原因
Because God has given us...
因为上帝给了我们
...one of the greatest gifts in the worId:
世界上最好的礼物
ChemicaIs.
化学！
Now, you peopIe, you Iike to go sit in church on Sunday, don't you?
你们这些人 在星期天去做礼拜，是吗？
You Iike to sit and watch the Super BowI.
你们喜欢坐着看超级杯比赛
CROWD: Yeah.
是
Sit on what?!
而你们坐在什么上面？
You sit on moIded, pIastic seats!
你们是坐在做好的塑胶椅上
MoIded to your we -fed behinds.
这样此可以让你们好好地坐
Now, I don't have to teII you that America Ieads the worId...
现在我不需要告诉你们 美国在这方面的
... n high-grade pIastics.
领先程度
We cannot afford a chemica -p astics gap.
我们无法承受 化学塑胶的差距
Now, isten to me.
现在，听我说…
Do you want...
你想要…
...our president of the United States sitting down...
我们的美国总统坐下来
...to write a peace treaty...
写一篇和平条约
...and have h s baIIpoint pen bust open...
让他的原子笔爆开后
...and the ink run out aII over his nice, cIean pants...
墨水弄脏他的 好看又干净的裤子
... n front of the worId Ieaders?
在全世界的领袖面前出挨吗？
CROWD: No. No.
不…
Now, we a know...
现在我们都知道
...that Iast week, haIf of this great nation of ours...
上星期全世界半数的国家
...aImost bit the buI et...
都遭受灾难
... f it wasn't for this man here.
如果不是他 后果不堪设想
And aI I can say is, thank the Lord for Superman.
我只能说成谢上苍 赐予我们超人
Superman, you saved our bacon...
超人，你解救了我们
...and I'd Iike to show our gratitude.
而我要表达我的成激
This s a smaII token of our appreciation...
小小意思 不成敬意
...to show to you for saving us from a chemicaI-pIant disaster.
成谢你让我们避免了 一场化学大灾难
Thank you very much, generaI.
将军，非常成谢
This is very nice. Thank you.
这真好，谢谢
It's very n ce.
非常好
Unknown. How am I supposed to know what ''unknown'' means?
未知，我要如何知道 什么是未知？
It means unknown. It means nobody knows what it means.
未知就是没有人会知道
-HeIIo, boss? WEBSTER: Gus?
- 哈罗，老板？ - 格斯？
-Gus Gorman here. -l know that. How did it go?
- 我是格斯高曼 - 我知道，情况如何？
You know how they're aIways trying to find the secret recipe...
是，你知道他们在找 烹调上的秘密
... n that ch cken in the bucket?
有多难吗？
And nobody seems to know the ingred ent...
而似乎没有人知道配方
...because t's unknown, right?
因为有未知的成分
In the Kryptonite there was an unknown eIement and Superman didn't die.
氪石也有一个不知道的成分 还有…超人没有死
He didn't die.
他没有死
I ask you to kiII Superman...
我要你去杀超人…
...and you're teIIing me you cou dn't even do that one s mpIe thing.
而你却告诉我 你无法做到这种简单的事情
He o?
哈罗？
He hasn't had an afternoon nap for years.
他好久没有睡午觉了
This is the biggest day of h s Iife. I don't know how to thank you.
我想今天是他最重要的日子 而我不知要如何成谢你
You d d with that wonderfuI Iunch.
那顿丰富的午餐已经表达谢意
Oh, weII, I do Iike to cook.
我是喜欢煮饭烧菜
-You'lI take some coffee? -Yes, pIease.
- 你喝咖啡吧？ - 好，谢谢
-Decaffe nated, of course. -Right.
- 低咖啡因的 - 对
Hello? Yes.
哈罗？是
What?
什么？
Oh, reaIIy?
真的吗？
Yeah, he's here.
是，他在这里
I'II teII him. Okay, thanks. Bye-bye.
我会告诉他，好的，谢谢 再见
Superman, that was my frend Betty.
超人，我的朋友贝蒂说
There's an accident on the br dge. A traiIer crashed through the raiI.
河流的桥上发生意外 一部卡车出了车祸
It's hanging off the bridge and the drver's in the cab.
车子悬在桥上 司机还在里面
I'm sorry. I hate to make you rush off.
很抱歉 我不是要赶你
WeII, there's no rush.
一点都不赶
-But the bridge-- -It's okay. I aIways get there on time.
- 但是在桥上… - 没关系，我会赶到的
Come on, et's re ax a IittIe.
来啊，我们休，急一下
It's unusuaI finding a good-Iooking girI Iike you aIone Iike this.
要找到像你这么漂亮的 单身女孩很不容易
Listen, are you sure you shouIdn't do something about the brdge?
听着 你确定桥那边没问题吗？
What bridge?
什么桥？
You're right.
你说得对！
I have to get going.
我必须要走了
OFFICER: Get h m out of there. Come on.
把他弄出来，快啊
Get him out! Get him out qu ck!
快点弄出来！
Come on. Get him away. That thing's gonna go.
弄出来，要掉下来了
MAN: Everybody okay? Joe?
大家还好吗？
What can I do to heIp?
我能帮上什么忙吗？
Not much of anything now.
现在没什么好帮的了
If on y you'd got here a minute sooner.
如果你能早点来，就好了
[SPEAKING ITAL AN]
（意大利文）
''At a speciaI session of the GeneraI AssembIy...
在一次特别的会议中
...178 countries voted to censure Superman...
有178个国家投票谴责超人
...with onIy CoIombia absta ning."
只有哥伦比亚一个弃权
I can teII you one thing.
我只能告诉你们
He wasn't so mean and nasty the other day in SmaI viIIe.
他在小镇并没有如此坏
In fact, he was so fuII of niceness...
事实上他真的很好
...I hated Iaying that big chunk of....
我不喜欢用这样的事情
Kryptonite. Don't you see?
氪石…
That stuff we ran off in the Iab wasn't a compIete faiIure after aII.
你没看出实验室的成果吗？ 并没有完全失败
Right after Gus gave it to h m, he started to turn into...
就在格斯给他这份礼物后 他就变得…
...an ornery, eviI, maIicious, se fish--
卑鄙、邪恶、心怀不轨、自私
-A normaI person. -Yes.
- 一个平常人！ - 对
And now that Superman is out of the nice-guy business....
而现在超人 就不会再做好事了
We can get to work on that oiI.
我们此可以进行石油计划了
ANNOUNCER: And now, tha suprame moment, as the last runner...
现在是极为重要的时刻 最后一位跑者…
...the one glven the great honor of lightlng the caramonial flame...
以无比荣誉的心态 手持圣火…
...runs the last lag of a marathon that began seven days ago...
跑完了为时七天的马拉松…
...as thls torch has been passed from athlata to athlete...
很多选手…
...for 970 mlles...
经过全国…
...across the country.
970哩
How can he say that pure categories have no objective mean ng...
他怎么能说单纯分类没有…
...in transcendentaI Iogic? What about synthetic un ty?
重要的逻辑？ 那综合性的连贯呢？
Hi, honey! Am I in your way?
嗨，甜心，我妨碍到你了吗？
-Stick around, you may Iearn something. -Hi, LoreIei.
- 在旁边看着或许你会学到什么 - 嗨，萝苗蕾！
AII the o tankers in the word are totaIIy controIIed by computers.
世界上所有的油轮 都由电脑控制
They te I them where to go, how much oiI to pick up...
电脑告诉他们要去哪里 要运多少油
...and where to deIiver it.
要去哪里
Don't they have captains on these ships?
他们在船上没船长吗？
Yes, but they don't need them.
有，但是不需要他们
That's a throwback to some sentimentaI, seafaring baIoney.
说起来真有点伤成
VERA: You wiII command the tankers to saiI toward a 50-miIe area...
你要下令这些油轮 朝一个在大西洋中央…
... n the middIe of the At antic Ocean.
五十哩的区域去
And do what?
然后要做什么？
And do nothing.
什么也不做
Just sit there.
就待在那里
How are aII the peop e gonna get their o ?
那人们要如何得到石油？
You catch on fast, oId buddy.
你反应真快，老兄
Every oiI pump in America is run by--
美国每一个油井都是由…
-Computers. know. -WiII you stop interrupt ng?!
- 由电脑控制，我知道 - 你不要打断我！
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
You wiII command the pumps to stop pumping.
你要下令 所有的油井停止供油
WEBSTER: Then I want you to program one speciaI command...
然后我要你设计一个 特别的程式
... nto aII these systems.
在所有的系统中
TeII them these orders are rreversibIe.
一个无法更改的程式
So t wou d be impossib e for anybody to switch them back.
没有人能够再把它改回来
Can you do this for me, o d buddy?
你办得到吗，老兄？
OId paI?
老友？
You know, you get your way a the time.
你一直要用你的方法去做
And it's not right.
这是不对的
I wanna know when I get a taste.
我要知道我有什么好处
I th nk you've aIready had a taste of freedom, haven't you?
我想你已经尝到 自由的滋味，不是吗？
Or wouId you prefer jaiI?
还是你想要坐牢？
You can't run that jaiI number on me.
你已经无法让我去坐牢了
Because I know I mean more to you out here doing th ngs for you...
因为我知道我在外面的价值
...than sitt ng in jaiI doing noth ng for nobody.
比在牢里面无所事事要高
I see.
我懂了
What do you want?
你要什么？
What? A wastelbasket?
什么？垃圾？
No. These are pIans.
不，这是计划
BIueprints.
这是蓝图
-For what? -A computer.
- 为什么？ - 一部电脑
-We've a ready got computers. -No, not Iike this.
- 我们已经有电脑了 - 不，不是这样的
There's not a computer Iike this in the whoIe worId anypIace.
目前世界上 没有一个电脑能像这样
It doesn't exist. You see...
目前不存在的 你要知道…
...we have to buiId it.
我们必须去建造新的电脑
What wiII it do?
那它会做什么？
Anything I teII it.
我所说的任何事情
What wi I it do for me?
那对我有何好处？
For you? It wiII do anything you teII me to teII it to do for you.
对你而官？任何你告诉我的事 我都可以帮你做
TeII me.
告诉我
GUS: F rst of aII, f anyone attacks this machine or anything...
首先如果任何人想要攻击它
...the computer counterattacks it.
电脑会自动反击
I mean, it f nds their weaknesses and wipes them out.
它会自动找到他们的弱点 解决对方
WEBSTER: Right, old buddy.
好，老友
You deal with my oil and l'll bulld you your machlna.
你帮我处理石油 我就建一部电脑给你
GUS: Okay, l'll do it.
好，我会做
But l'm not so sure about thls lrravarsible business.
只是我无法复原的程式 没有太大的把握
They aII kind of went-- What the heI ?
他们全部停工了 怎么搞的？
WEBSTER: That's it. The Iast tanker.
就这样了，最后一艘油轮
They're aII mine now. AII mine.
他们全都是，全都是我的了
VERA: Not quite.
并不是
What's that in the upper-middIe quadrant?
在上面那一个是什么？
It's a tanker.
是油轮
And it's go ng the wrong way.
它走错路了
Skipper?
船长？
There it is again. "Proceed immediateIy to...
又来了 马上到…
...Iat tude 30 north, Iongitude 45 west.
北纬30度，西经45度
There await further orders."
等待进一步的指示
HeII, that's the middIe of the AtIantic.
那是大西洋的中央
I'm not taking my ship there just to await further orders...
我才不要把我的船闭到那里 等待什么指示
...no matter what that says.
才不管上面说什么
We're supposed to go to MetropoIis, and we're go ng to Metropo s.
我们该去大都会 我们此去大都会
AII right.
好了
MAN 1: That's where she is. Yeah.
她在那里
MAN 2: Come on, get it up there.
好了，到上面
OFF CER [ON PA]: Mlss?
小姐？
Miss, can you hear me?
小姐，你听到我了吗？
Llstan, we are hera to help you.
听着，我们是到这里来帮你的
Don't jump. l rapeat, do not jump!
不要跳，我重复，不要跳！
Thought you'd never get here.
我以为你永远不会来此
Don't expect me to save you. I don't do that anymore.
我希望你不会指望我来救你 因为我再也不这么做了
Don't worry.
别担心
I'm Iong past saving.
我不需要被救
WeII...
嗯…
...don't Iet me keep you from anything.
别让我耽误你的事情
I'm not in a rush.
我并没有其他的事情
What did you have in mind?
你在想些什么？
Lots of things.
很多事情
Oh, yeah?
是吗？
If you'II just do me one ittIe favor first.
如果你可以帮我一个小忙
What's that?
要做什么？
WeII....
嗯…
See, there's this Iitt e boat...
有一艘船
...and it's not going where it's supposed to go and....
没有去该去的地方
SAILOR: Stop aII engines!
停止所有引擎！
Hi.
嗨
How about a I ttIe apres-ski?
要不要先来点前奏？
Champagne?
香槟？
Take your turn I ke everybody eIse!
不要插队！
Stop it!
瑞，不要
He's coming over here, Martha.
他要过来了，摇上窗子
MAN 1 : Don't you do that!
你不可以
MAN 2: Hit him with your handbag!
用包包打他啊！
HeIp me! PIease, heIp me. Somebody's beating up my husband.
救命！请救我 有人正在打我先生
-I've gotta caII the poIice. -Jack, go with her, okay?
- 我要去报警 - 杰克，你跟她去吧
The th rd one today, and at n ght t's worse.
这是今天第三次了 晚上会更糟糕
Somebody's behind this.
后面一定有人搞鬼
You can't teII me there's no oiI.
你别告诉我没有石油
You can't say someone's not getting rich off this.
你别告诉我 没有人因此发财
Someone's aIways getting rich.
永远都会有人发财
You know who suffers? The smaII guy.
而你知道是谁受苦吗？小市民
NEWSCASTER: Tha East Coast gets the brunt of the splll.
东部地区一片混乱 你们快点把东西弄进去！
[WORKERS SHOUT INDISTINCTLY]
嘿，大伙，慢一点
No, I cannot go out with you tonight.
不，我今晚不能跟你出去
No. I'm busy tomorrow night too.
我明天晚上也很忙
Oh, yeah? Doing what?
是吗？要做什么？
I'II think of something. Look...
我会想到一些，听着…
-...I gotta go. Ricky needs me. -Lana.
- 我要走了，瑞奇需要我 - 拉娜！
Brad, pIease stop caIIing me. I've to d you!
布莱德，我告诉过你 不要再打给我了
WeII, you Iisten to me, huh?
你听我说
You better start apprec at ng o d Brad.
你最好要开始威谢我
What eIse you got in SmaIIv I e?
否则你在小镇还能怎样？
What eIse have I got in SmaIIv e?
我在小镇能怎样？
I think I got the right answer.
我想我有答案
So do I.
我也是
SmaIIviIIe Airport, what fIights do you have to MetropoIis tomorrow?
小镇机场 明天有飞机去大都会吗？
-Where do I put this? -Over there.
- 你要我放哪里？ - 放在那里
-Where do you want this? -Put it up there.
- 这个你要我放哪里？
[PEOPLE CHATTER INDISTINCTLY]
（圣路易旅社 小酒馆）
WOMAN: Are you kidding? I'm not going in there.
你闻玩笑吗？我才不要进去
Hey, hey. Come on.
嘿，嘿，别这样
MAN: Just Ieave him a one.
不要管他
I can't get through. Someth ng's happening.
我过不去了，小姐 那里发生了事情
MAN: Hey, Iook! Superman's drunk!
看！超人喝醉了！
-I wanna see what's happen ng here. -Ricky. Ricky!
- 我要看看这里发生了什么事 - 瑞奇…
-Ricky. -Yeah, that's right.
- 瑞奇 - 对，没错
-Thank you. -It's a disgrace, that's what it is.
- 谢谢 - 真可耻，真是的
I' I teII you, nobody's ever gonna trust that creep again.
我告诉你 没有人会再相信这个败类
He's washed up.
他完蛋了！
What are you Iooking at? Huh?
你们在看什么？
RICKY: Excuse me. Superman? It's me, Ricky.
对不起，超人？是我，瑞奇
Ricky from SmaIIviIIe.
小镇的瑞奇
TeI them you won't hurt anybody!
超人，告诉他们 你不会伤害任何人！
He's changed.
他变了
No! Maybe he's just s ck.
不，或许他只是生病了
Superman, pIease get better!
超人，请好起来！
LANA: He's not I stening to you.
他没有听到你说的，瑞奇
Yes, he s. He can hear me. He's got super-hearing.
他会听到，他听得到的 他有顺风耳
Superman, you're just in a sIump!
超人，你只是陷入低潮！
You'II be great again!
你会好起来的！
You can do it, Superman!
你办得到的，超人！
Superman, you can haar ma, can't you?
超人，你听得到我，对吗？
Suparman, you're just ln a slump.
超人，你只是陷入低潮
You'll be great agaln. You can do it, Superman.
你会好起来的 你办得到的，超人
Superman, you can haar ma, can't you?
超人，你听得到我，对吗？
MAN 1 : He's gone nuts!
他疯了
Come on!
快点！
I can g ve as good as I get.
我尽力了
Oh, yeah? A right, come on! Come on!
是吗？好啊，来啊！快啊！
Come on! Come on!
来啊！快啊！
What's the matter, Kent? Too warm for you, huh?
怎么了，肯特？ 太热了吗？
Come on, chicken! Come and get me.
快点，懦夫！来抓我啊
You've been on my nerves a Iong t me!
你已经把我给惹毛了
You aIways wanted to fIy, Kent.
你一直想要飞起来，肯特
Now's your chance.
现在机会来了
Skipper!
船长…
God, wouId you Iook at that!
天啊，你看看！
WEBSTER: Mlss Loralel Ambrosia lsn't at home rlght now.
萝苗蕾小姐 目前不在家
But lf you'd cara to laave a massage...
但是如果你有重要事
...why not dellver lt to her ln person?
何不此当面跟她说呢？
So you'va flnally shown your true coIors.
你终于展现出原来的你了
Wall, lf you're looking for us, here's where you'Il flnd us.
如果你想找我们 这里是你找到我们的地方
Do drop in.
请快来
LORELEI: Wow, this is fun!
这真好玩！
Fun? The fun's just starting.
好玩？好玩的事情才开始
Wait tiII Superman f nds us, then you'l see some fun.
等到超人找到我们 你们此会知道什么叫做好玩
Wait, you gonna mess with Superman?
等一下，你要搞超人？
VERA: Let's go. I want to be ready for him when he faIIs into our trap.
走吧 我要在他进入陷阱前准备好
I just don't see why you can't baIIoon down Iike the rest of us.
我就是不懂你为何不能 像我们一样搭热汽球
WeII....
这…
No way.
不可以…
I just don't beIieve a man can fIy.
我只是不相信人可以飞
LORELEI: Watch out, horsy!
小心点，马儿！
Don't , don't , don't .
不要…
Just don't try to fIy.
不要想要飞
Don't try to f y!
别飞！
WiII you get out of my way!
你不要档住我的路
-Hurry! Hurry up! -I am hurrying.
- 快，快点 - 我很快了
LORELEI: I can't see anything. VERA: Turn on the Iight.
- 我什么也看不到 - 把灯打开
LORELEI: Where's the Iight switch? VERA: Where do you usuaIIy find it?
- 灯的开关在哪里？ - 通常灯的开关在哪里？
LORELEI: I don't know. I guess I'lI check the doorway.
我不知道，我检查一下入口处
God, it's pitch-bIack in here. Oh, that's better.
天啊，这里真黑，这样好多了！
Wow, what a jukebox!
好棒的设备
WEBSTER: I toId you, didn't ?
我告诉过你们嘛，不是吗？
There. The uItimate computer!
好了，这就是超极限电脑
It does everything a computer can do and 1000 things none of them can do.
它会所有普通电脑会做的事情 还有其他电脑不会做的事情
VERA: Let's give it a dry run.
来吧，让我们来试试看
WEBSTER: Wait a minute. We've gotta wait for Gus.
等一下，我们要等格斯
VERA: Who needs Gus?
谁需要格斯？
-He's the onIy one who can operate it. VERA: Like fish he is!
- 只有他会控制电脑 - 简单得很！
I know enough about computers to put a Ph.D. to shame.
我比博士都还了解 如何使用电脑
Come now, brother dear, you didn't think...
拜托，老哥，你以为…
...I was gonna Iet that IittIe man run the show, did you?
我真的会让那个小黑人玩吗？
Why don't peons tidy up when they're done?
工人做好了 怎么不收拾好呢？
Come on, Bubba, t's showtime.
快点，老哥，好戏登场了！
Engage those buttons to act vate the aIpha circuit...
用那些按钮去启动阿法回路
...and ock the moduIar grd.
锁住系数
You! Activate circuits 29 through W-7...
你！放动29到W7处的线路
...and start fuII-power coordinates on exterior defensive systems.
然后闲启全部能量 展闻防御系统功能
In other words, push this red button.
换句话说，按红色按钮
How did you know about that?
你怎么知道的？
He's here!
他来了！
VERA: Good. Let's give him something to worry about.
很好，给他点事做做吧
Now, Iet's see....
现在我们来看看
Tracking systems ocked.
导弹系统启动
Let the games beg n.
让游戏开始吧
LORELEI: Don't tense up now, honey.
别太兴奋，甜心
VERA: Come on, Bubba, you're wasting your rockets.
拜托，老哥，你在浪费火箭
Come on, Superman!
加油，超人！
Let him have it, Ross.
把他干掉，罗斯
VERA: Bubba, keep f ring.
老哥，继续发射
Keep him occupied whiIe I get the MX ready.
让他没时问顾到别的 我要准备飞弹
GUS: What the heII is go ng on?
怎么回事？
VERA: You keep your rockets coming. He won't notice the missiIe tiII too Iate!
你继续发射火箭 等他发现飞弹说来不及了
VERA: So much for your cat ike ref exes.
你也不过尔尔
Oh, God!
天啊！
No more. Look, you sit.
拜托…不要…坐
Sit, sit!
对…坐下…
HeIp!
救命！
HeIIo? Forget you, jackass!
哈罗！不要乱动
WEBSTER: That's him out of the way.
他就这样完了
Sis, how wouId you ike to controI aII the worId's weapons systems?
老妹 你要控制全世界的武器系统吗？
Baby!
宝贝！
It's Daddy!
是老爸！
Hey, what are you doing with my baby?
你要对我的宝贝做什么？
Gus, oId buddy, genius. Come up and join the fun.
格斯，老搭档，上来一起玩吧
He's stiII com ng. Arm the inner defenses.
他又过来了，启动内部防御
AII rght, the game's over.
好了，维斯伯，游戏结束了
Hi, honey.
嗨，甜心！
I don't know you, Iady.
我不认识你，小姐
But the other night....
但是在那个晚上…
I'm sorry, but that wasn't me.
很抱歉，但是那不是我
That guy's gone.
那家伙走了
And you're next, Webster.
而你是下一位，维斯伯！
WEBSTER: Never underestimate the power of computers.
千万别低估，电脑的力量
How do you I ke it?
你喜欢吗？
SUPERMAN: I think it's typicaI of peopIe Iike you, Webster.
维斯伯，你就像其他人一样
Instead of heIping others, the four of you just wanna heIp yourseIves.
你们四个所做的 只是想满足自己的需求
Four of you?
你们四个？
You mean, us? Four? Wait--
你说我们四个？等等
Hey, man!
老兄…
That's onIy his Iast name. He Iikes to be caIIed "Superman."
他只有一个名字 他希望别人称他超人
See, I'm not w th them, Superman.
这样，我跟他们不同国，超人
You couId've fooIed me, mister.
你是骗不了我的，先生！
WEBSTER: That's very good.
那个很好！
VERA: Let's see how Iong he can carry on wthout any a r.
让我们看看没有空气 他能撑多久
He's sti I coming! He's going to get me!
他又来了！ 他要来抓我！
Don't bet on it!
才不会
You're hurting him.
你在伤害他
-That's Kryptonite! VERA: Yes.
- 那是氪石！ - 是的
-This time we got it rght! -You're a genius.
- 这一次我们做对了 - 你是个天才
You've invented a machine that can find anybody's weak spot.
你所发明的机器 可以找到任何人的弱点
CongratuIations, oId buddy.
恭喜了，老弟
You'II go down in history as the man who kiIIed Superman!
你将留名青史 因为你干掉了超人
I'm-- No.
我不要
Superman!
超人！
No!
不！
VERA: Where do you think you're going? WEBSTER: Never mind.
- 等一下…你以为你要去哪里？ - 别管他了
WEBSTER: Turn the power up. LORELEI: Hasn't he had enough?
- 增加能量 - 你不觉得他的能量够了吗？
WEBSTER: Turn it up!
再增加！
Power! More power!
能量！要更多能量！
Seventy-five. Current 7.75.
75… 流量7点75
There's a current Ieve of 7 that is not supposed to be on bar--
这里有七级的电流 但是不是在这里，所以就…
Oh, here it is!
在这里！
WEBSTER: What's going on?
发生了什么事？
I don't know. The power's gone.
我不知道，没有电了
Gus must have puIIed the pIug out.
一定是格斯关掉的
It worked.
成功了，真的成功了
It worked! I got t!
我成功了…我…
WEBSTER: What have you got?
你做了什么？
-Give me that screw. -This screw?
- 把螺丝给我 - 这个螺丝？
-That screw. -Never!
- 那个螺丝 - 绝不！
WEBSTER: Hey, wait. I can't see.
嘿，等等，我看不见了
VERA: What?
什么？
HoIy--!
天啊…！
LORELEI: No! Make it stop!
不…阻止它！
I can't ! t's out of controI!
我没办法！它失去控制了！
But how? Where's it getting the power from?
但是怎么会呢？ 哪里来的能量？
It's feeding itseIf.
它自己弄的
It wants to Iive!
它要活下去
It's this thing here. We'lI go to the zoo.
就是这里，我们去动物园
I'II do that tomorrow, and then we'lI go on to the--
我们明天去，然后再去别的…
-What's happening? -It's okay, Ricky.
- 发生什么事？我怕 - 没关系，瑞奇
Put the Iights on!
把灯打开
Stop t! You're kiIIing him!
住手！你会杀了他！
Stop it!
住手！
Hey. Put me down!
放我下来！
Don't Ieave us a one in here! Superman!
别把我们留在这里，超人
Oh, I get it.
我懂了
The coaxiaI energy shaft is engaging the grid source factor. Right.
能源轴是能源出处，对
We're through, frogface. I'm spIitt ng.
我们完了，我要先溜了！
Hey, wa t a minute!
嘿，等一下！
GirIs. GirIs, come out of there!
女孩！快离开那里！
HeIp me! PIease!
救我！拜托！
Sis?
老妹？
Oh, my God.
我的天啊！
What is that?
那是什么？
Lore ei!
萝苗蕾
Sis, t's your Bubba!
老妹，我是你哥，不要…
HeIp me. HeIp!
救我！
Superman!
超人！
Honey!
甜心！
Honey, 'm stuck here! HeIp! What about me?
甜心，我卡在这里！救命！ 那我呢？
Look out!
小心！
Bubba?
老哥？
Thank you, brother.
谢谢，兄弟
ReguIar or premium?
普通还是高级的？
She hasn't had a drink n so ong, give her a tankfuI of the good stuff.
管他的，她好久没有加油了 给她最好的
How you doing?
你觉得如何，格斯？
P ease don't taIk to me. I'm having enough troubIe hang ng on.
请不要跟我说话 我的麻烦已经够多了
Okay, we'lI go sIow. You're perfectIy safe.
好，我们可以慢一点 你非常安全
I'm not gonna argue w th you.
我不会跟你争辩这点
I mean, any man who can trick my machine can do anything.
能够破解我的机器 就能做到任何事情
How did you beat my defenses?
你是如何破解防御的？
Those defenses are good as Iong as t didn't know it's n troubIe.
那个机器是很厉害 但它不知道会有麻烦
This t me it didn't see the danger. I went in with pIa n oId acid.
这一次它不知道危险的地方 我只是把特殊化学物拿来
It didn't know that when acid gets hot, it' eat through anything.
当那种酸到达一定温度时 它就会毁掉所有的东西
-Watch the trees. -Whoa!
小心树！
I guess it died of acid indigestion.
我想这次它死于酸性消化不良
But what's gonna happen to Ross and the Iadies?
那我的老板 和两位小姐会如何？
They're gonna have to see the poIice. It's not your probIem anymore.
他们要去和警察谈谈了 那不是你的问题了
Are we in MetropoIis yet?
我们到大都会了吗？
Nope. We're just gonna make a Iitt e stop right over there.
还没，我们要在那里停一下
We're on the ground, Gus. Morning.
我们降落了，格斯
-You okay, Supe? -I'm fine.
- 你没事吧，超人？ - 我没事
Excuse me a second.
对不起
Can you guys spare one of these?
你们可以给我一些这个吗？
-Sure, Superman. -It s Superman, isn't it?
- 当然可以，超人 - 这是超人，是吧？
Are you kidding? Is that--?
你在闲玩笑吗？
Didn't you see us f y out of the sky?
没看到我们在天上飞吗？
We're the onIy two men who can fIy. "Is it Superman?"
只有我和超人会飞耶 这位是超人吗？
SUPERMAN: Just right.
这就对了
Okay, Gus, Iet's go.
好，格斯，走吧！
I was afraid you'd say that. I thought I'd take the bus.
我就怕你这样说 我想我还是坐公车好了
WeII, suit yourse f. Does your boss have a computer here?
随便你啦 你们老板有电脑吗？
Yeah, he got a IittIe bitty one about that big.
是，他有一台小电脑
You te I him he can do a ot worse than to give Gus Gorman here a job.
你告诉他 格斯会做很多电脑相关事情
Wow, thank you, Supe.
谢谢你，超人
Take care.
保重了
I'II see you around.
我们再会了
SUPERMAN: So Iong.
再见
Take t easy, man.
保重，老兄
WeII, you got good references, so if you want that job....
有人强力谁荐你 你想要这份工作吗？
Nah, this is not for me. I think I'lI take that bus.
不要了，这不适合我 我想我要去搭公车
Can you te me where the bus station is?
能告诉我车站在哪里吗？
Yeah, about n ne, 10 miIes over there.
是的，到那里要走9或10哩路
Nine or 10 miIes. Okay.
9或10哩路！好吧
Hey. You reaIIy fIew with him?
你真的跟他一起飞吗？
Superman? Have you ever seen Superman before?
超人？ 你们以前见过超人吗？
No.
没有
Oh, you don't know about me and h m? Me and Superman?
你不知道我和他的关系？ 我和超人？
Yeah, we go way back together.
是，我们都是一起的
We aIways, usuaIIy, sometimes, we....
我们一直，通常，有时候是…
Nine or 10 miIes?
9或10哩路吗？
I think I'II waIk.
我想我用走的
Yeah, I' waIk.
对，我用走的
Yeah.
对
CIark.
克拉克
What a nice surprse! Come n.
真是惊讶，请进
-Gosh. Hi, Mr. Kent. -Hi, Ricky.
- 嗨，肯特先生！ - 嗨，瑞奇！
-Guess who Mom's hav ng d nner with. -Who?
- 猜猜看今晚谁要来吃饭？ - 是谁？
Superman!
超人！
Yeah, that's what I came to teII you.
对了，这就是我要来告诉你的事
Superman said to teII you he's sorry...
超人要告诉你，他真的很抱歉
...but he's run into a probIem and he won't be ab e to have dinner with you.
但是他有些事情 他今晚无法与你吃饭了
-I guess he misses a Iot of d nners. -Yeah.
- 我猜他错过了很多次的晚餮 - 是啊
WouId you mind settI ng for me?
你介意我和你吃吗？
Any day.
怎么会？
-I'II get my things. -Okay.
- 我去拿东西 - 好
You know, Lana, I was ta king to Superman the other day.
拉娜，我那天和超人聊天
You know, he and I, we taIk a Iot.
你知道，他和我 我们聊了很多
And he feIt badIy about you having to pawn your diamond ring.
他很难过 你当了你的钻石戒指
WeII, he found....
他发现这个…
He found this one just Iy ng around.
他在地上发现这个
He wanted you to have this.
他要你收下
Wow, a r ng from Superman!
超人送的戒指！
-It's okay. I got it. -Sorry.
- 没关系，我来处理 - 抱歉
Look at that.
你看
LANA: Oh, CIark. -It's okay.
- 克拉克 - 没关系
It fits.
大小刚好
It Iooks reaIIy pretty.
真好看
Thank you.
谢谢
-Brad.
- 布莱德
Son of a bitch.
你这个混蛋
Kent, I hate you.
肯特，我恨你
I've aIways hated you.
我一直都恨你
-You know why? -No.
- 你知道为何吗？ - 不知道
-Because you're nice. -Not rea y.
- 因为你人很好 - 也不是真的…
And n ce guys finish Iast.
好人要完蛋了
PERRY: Lois, I've got to hand it to you.
露薏丝，我必须要交给你
Who e se couId turn a vacat on into a story...
还有谁能够将三星期的假期
...that'lI bIow the Iid off of corruption in the Caribbean?
变成揭发 加勒比海腐败内慕的报导呢？
I knew I was on to something when that taxi drver k dnapped me.
当计程车司机绑架我时 我就知道不对劲了
Lois, you're terrfic.
露薏丝，你真棒
I have to be. Seems I've got some new compet tion.
我必须这样 我似乎遇到竞争对手了
The story that you wrote on the cIass reunion?
你所写的同学聚会
-I thought it was terrfic. -Thanks.
- 我觉得太好了 - 谢谢
And fascinating. I Iiked the part about the ttIe girI back home.
非常吸引人 尤其是家乡女孩的那部分
I'II take you to unch and you teII me about it.
我带你去吃午饭 你把详情告诉我
I'd Iove to, but I'm having Iunch with Mr. White's new secretary.
我很想要，露薏丝，但是今天 我要和怀特先生的新秘书吃饭
-Hi, Lana. -Hi, Clark.
- 嗨，拉娜 - 嗨，克拉克
Lana. Lois, say heIIo to Lana Lang, SmaIIv I e's newest gift to MetropoIis.
露薏丝，这位是蓝拉娜… 小镇献给大都会的最新礼物
I'm gIad to meet you. I Iike your wrting a Iot.
很高兴见到你，莲恩小姐 我很喜欢你的作品
Thank you.
谢谢
I Iike your sparkIer a Iot.
我很喜欢你的钻石
Me too. I couIdn't beIieve it when CIark gave it to me.
我也是，当克拉克给我的时候 我也无法相信
-CIark gave it to you? -Yes.
- 克拉克给你的？ - 是啊
SECRETARY: Mr. White.
怀特先生
Mr. White, Iook what I've got for you.
怀特先生，看看我弄了什么给你
PeopIe, I am n Iove w th this machine!
各位，我爱死这部机器了！
Mr. White. excuse me, but I have a coupIe of errands to run before Iunch.
对不起，如果你们不介意… 但是我午餮前还有事情要做
-Go ahead, Mr. White. -Where's the handIe?
- 请吧，怀特先生 - 手把在哪里？
There is no handIe. You just push the button.
没有手把 你只要按按钮
[SPEAKING ITAL AN]
（意大利文）